SCOTT FERNALD

Senior Software Engineer

scott.fernald1110@gmail.com • +1 770 872 7817 • Clearwater, FL

Summary

Persistent professional equipped with 13+ years of comprehensive experience in the Software Development industry. Provides strong technical direction across multiple projects. Experienced with the full software development lifecycle from planning to launch. Responsible and articulate individual with strengths in solutions optimization, mobile and cloud solutions, and global project management. A big fan of basketball and soccer. A self-motivated, avid learner.

Education

New College of Florida

B.S. in Computer Science

09/2007 - 04/2011

Experience

Goffstown, NH Fortunes Tech Senior Software Engineer

01/2022 - Present

- · Mentored and provided technical quidance to an engineering team of 10+ members.
- · Led and participated in the development of various web and mobile applications using cutting-edge technologies, including React, React Native, Next.js, Node.js, Python, and Golang.
- Actively contributed to code reviews, ensuring code quality, maintainability, and adherence to best practices.
- Responsible for the DevOps role using GCP, AWS, Kubernetes and Docker.

Denver, CO Velocity Global

Senior Software Engineer

05/2020 - 12/2021

- Led the development of Customer Experience Platform(CXP)-client company's internal managing platform with a team of senior developers leveraging React, NestJS, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, Docker, and AWS.
- Successfully built a semi-auto mechanism that integrated Glean API-OpenAI platform into CXP using MERN stack and ChatGPT APIs.
- · Participated in the development of a Document Management Platform(DOCX), providing FormKiQ and OPA solutions, and building high-performance RESTful APIs using TypeScript, Node.js, Golang, and GraphQL, handling an average of 10,000 requests per minute.
- Collaborated with staff and principal engineers to provide proof of concept, TDD, and design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements.
- Mentored less experienced team members to follow the advanced principles and conventions.

Pittsford, NY Sutherland

Software Engineer

01/2018 - 02/2020

- · Served as a lead developer for building a complex project for managing painting proposals with POS, scheduling, task management, work orders, invoicing, and payment system.
- · Led the end-to-end development process, including database design, frontend and back-end development, and AWS deployment, utilizing Node, React, React Native and MongoDB as the tech stack.
- Overcame the challenge of limited payment integration options in Malaysia by conducting extensive research and selecting the best available service.
- Developed the MVP within a tight timeframe of just 6 months, ensuring its successful adoption by customers who are now actively utilizing the platform's car and motorcycle lending services.
- Worked on managing the Git workflow, reviewing the tasks completed and code.
- Built RESTful and functional APIs that run on Node.js and use a connected PostgreSQL database.

Clearwater, FL Enumerate

Software Engineer

09/2016 - 11/2017

- · Worked with a team of developers to migrate the existing UI from AngularJS to React, add an extensive list of new features, and add unit tests and component tests for all features, key users, and roles.
- Integrated a third-party identity service, OKTA, and related UI flows, including account activation, login, forgot password, and session management using JWT, token validation, and session cookies.
- Assisted in enhancing the schema for a RESTful API to optimize its consumption by Apollo Client.
- Revamped the entire components and pages with new Figma designs.

Experience

Clearwater, FL Enumerate 03/2014 - 09/2016

Front End Engineer

- Developed frontend applications using React, Redux, Typescript, Styled-components, GraphQL, Bootstrap, etc.
- Built user interface, kanban board, data visualizations, and designed overall user experience.
- Wrote high-quality code covered with the unit and e2e tests.
- Implemented UI for visualization Nested Sets structure of documents display in a drag & drop file structure, files and folders view, creation, deleting, and editing.
- Supported the CTO with various management tasks as high-level architectural decisions.

Clearwater, FL **TPGi**

Software Engineer

05/2011 - 02/2014

- · Participated in the initial wave of developers learning and implementing Laravel, WordPress, and React.
- · Built a feature to integrate all scheduled tasks and projects in the user calendar with our one-way syncing with API Token and wrote
- Engineered a Node.js/Express server, utilizing routing and middleware capabilities to make request calls to an SQL database.
- Utilized tools like LESS and SASS for CSS development.
- Developed iOS & android map research mobile application from scratch to deploy.

Skills

Client-side: React · React · Next.js · VueJS · Redux · SCSS · Material UI · Tailwind CSS · Storybook · Jest · Cypress

Server-side: Node.js · ExpressJS · NestJS · Python · Golang · Ruby · Laravel · MySQL · PostgreSQL · Elasticsearch · GraphQL · MongoDB

DevOps: Docker · Kubernetes · Azure · AWS · Google Cloud Platform

Volunteering

AllClear

Senior Full Stack Developer

03/2020 - 05/2020

AllClear is an open-source project for helping to fight COVID-19 by providing the fastest way to find a nearby test center.

Worked as a senior full stack developer and a member of 30 person volunteers, committed to an open-source project for helping to fight COVID-19.

Freelancing



Treelance Full Stack Developer

02/2019 - 12/2021 Toptal



📅 Freelance Full Stack Developer

04/2017 - 10/2020 Upwork

Certification

React Expert Certificate — Hackerrank

Backend Developer Certificate — Triplebyte

Find me online



linkedin.com/in/scottfernald1110



https://scottfernald.netlify.app